Draper Corporation Glass Plate Negatives 6612 GPN
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Series B: 8 x 10 inch negatives.
  - Sucking thread through the shuttle eye, Draper Company, 1911 (Box 179, Folder 871)
    Negative no.B871. February 15, 1911. Image depicts an unidentified man on the far right demonstrating how mill operatives would suck the thread through the eye of a shuttle by using a shuttle and a skeleton. The man holds the shuttle to the skeleton's mouth. Mill operatives would draw the thread through their mouths to help smooth it and make it easier to draw through the eye of the shuttle. However, sucking on cotton thread could eventually cause lung problems and did so in many mill operatives. The unidentified man wears a three-piece suit and wire-rimmed glasses. Whether he is a Draper Company executive or someone else is unknown. See also Negative 872 and Negative 873, in this box, for other views of this man; Negative 870 and Negative 874, in this box, for a younger man demonstrating the same thing; and Box 178, Negative 862 and Negative 863 to see a male mill operative demonstrate this operation on a mill floor. As the Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and did not manufacture cloth, it is unclear what relation this photograph has to Draper unless it was to demonstrate something with their looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 871 for print of this negative.
  - Sucking thread through the shuttle eye, Draper Company, 1911 (Box 179, Folder 872)
    Negative no.B872. February 15, 1911. Image depicts an unidentified man demonstrating how mill operatives would suck the thread through the eye of a shuttle by using a shuttle and a skeleton. The hand of the skeleton (the skeleton's arm is supported by the hand of the man) holds the shuttle to its mouth (the shuttle is supported by the man's other hand). Mill operatives would draw the thread through their mouths to help smooth it and make it easier to draw through the eye of the shuttle. However, sucking on cotton thread could eventually cause lung problems and did so in many mill operatives. The unidentified man wears a three-piece suit and wire-rimmed glasses. Whether he is a Draper Company executive or someone else is unknown. See also Negative 871 and Negative 873, in this box, for other views of this man; Negative 870 and Negative 874, in this box, for a younger man demonstrating the same thing; and Box 178, Negative 862 and Negative 863 to see a male mill operative demonstrate this operation on a mill floor. As the Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and did not manufacture cloth, it is unclear what relation this photograph has to Draper unless it was to demonstrate something with their looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 872 for print of this negative.
  - Sucking thread through the shuttle eye, Draper Company, 1911 (Box 179, Folder 873)
    Negative no.B873. February 15, 1911. Image depicts an unidentified man demonstrating how mill operatives would suck the thread through the eye of a shuttle by using a shuttle and a skeleton. The hand of the skeleton (the skeleton's arm is supported by the hand of the man) holds the shuttle to its mouth (the shuttle is supported by the man's other hand). Mill operatives would draw the thread through their mouths to help smooth it and make it easier to draw through the eye of the shuttle. However, sucking on cotton thread could eventually cause lung problems and did so in many mill operatives. The unidentified man wears a three-piece suit and wire-rimmed glasses. Whether he is a Draper Company executive or someone else is unknown. See also Negative 871 and Negative 872, in this box, for other views of this man; Negative 870 and Negative 874, in this box, for a younger man demonstrating the same thing; and Box 178, Negative 862 and Negative 863 to see a male mill operative demonstrate this operation on a mill floor. As the Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and did not manufacture cloth, it is unclear what relation this photograph has to Draper unless it was to demonstrate something with their looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 873 for print of this negative.
  - Sucking thread through the shuttle eye, Draper Company, 1911 (Box 179, Folder 874)
    Negative no.B874. February 15, 1911. Image depicts an unidentified young man demonstrating how mill operatives would suck the thread through the eye of a shuttle by using a shuttle and a skeleton. The man holds a shuttle to the mouth of the skeleton. Mill operatives would draw the thread through their mouths to help smooth it and make it easier to draw through the eye of the shuttle. However, sucking on cotton thread could eventually cause lung problems and did so in many mill operatives. The unidentified man wears a suit with a sweater vest and dark tie. Whether he is a Draper Company executive or someone else is unknown. See also Negative 871, Negative 872, and Negative 873, in this box, for views of another man demonstrating the same thing; Negative 870, in this box, for another view of this man, and Box 178, Negative 862 and Negative 863 to see a male mill operative demonstrate this operation on a mill floor. As the Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms, and did not manufacture cloth, it is unclear what relation this photograph has to Draper unless it was to demonstrate something with their looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 874 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, April 3, 1911 (Box 180, Folder 883)
    Negative no.B883. April 3, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings. Two workmen stand in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of it (at least three stories high). See also Box 181, Negative 896 through Negative 898, which show the pile a month later, and Box 185, Negative 934, Negative 935, and Negative 937 which show the pile two months later. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 883 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, May 12, 1911 (Box 181, Folder 896)
    Negative no.B896. May 12, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings. One man stands in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of it (at least three stories high); two others can be glimpsed at the far right end of the pile. See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile a month earlier. See Negative 897 and Negative 898, in this box, for other views of this man in front of the scrap pile taken on this date. See Box 185, Negative 934, Negative 935, and Negative 937 for views of the scrap pile taken a month after this one. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 896 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, May 12, 1911 (Box 181, Folder 897)
    Negative no.B897. May 12, 1911. Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, May 12, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings. One man stands in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of it (at least three stories high). See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile a month earlier and is a closer view that does not show the extent of the pile shown here. See Negative 896 and Negative 898, in this box, for other views of this man in front of the scrap pile taken on this date. See Box 185, Negative 934, Negative 935, and Negative 937 for views of the scrap pile taken a month after this one. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 897 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, May 12, 1911 (Box 181, Folder 898)
    Negative no.B898. May 12, 1911. Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, May 12, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings (which are off to the right in this image). One man stands in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of it (at least three stories high). See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile a month earlier and is a closer view that does not show the extent of the pile shown here. See Negative 896 and Negative 897, in this box, for other views of this man in front of the scrap pile taken on this date. See Box 185, Negative 934, Negative 935, and Negative 937 for views of the scrap pile taken a month after this one. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 2, Item 898 for print of this negative.
  - Draper Company Exhibit in Mechanics Hall, 1910 (Box 183, Folder 915)
    Negative no.B915. Image depicts an exhibit of Draper Company looms at Mechanics Hall in 1910. The location of Mechanics Hall is unknown, but it does not seem to resemble the interior of Mechanics Hall in Worcester, Massachusetts Image is taken from the balcony of the hall, looking down on a display of Draper Company looms, but from a slightly different angle than seen in Negative 916, in this box. Two signs for Draper Company hang above the display. The balcony across from the photographer is hung with banners and an American flag; it contains mannequins dressed in clothing. A sign at the far left of the balcony display reads "Wm. Filene's Sons Co." Signs in the bottom right corner of the image point downstairs to the cement and concrete construction display. The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Massachusetts, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Negative 916, in this box, for another view of this exhibit. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 915 for print of this negative.
  - Draper Company Exhibit in Mechanics Hall, 1910 (Box 183, Folder 916)
    Negative no.B916. Image depicts an exhibit of Draper Company looms at Mechanics Hall in 1910. The location of Mechanics Hall is unknown, but it does not seem to resemble the interior of Mechanics Hall in Worcester, Massachusetts Image is taken from the balcony of the hall, looking down on a display of Draper Company looms. Two signs for Draper Company hang above the display. The balcony across from the photographer is hung with banners and an American flag; it contains mannequins dressed in clothing. A woman in a light-colored dress with dark stripes on it stands between the Draper looms; she is identified in Negative 918, in this box, as Mrs. Hardwick. The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Massachusetts, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See Negative 915, in this box, for another view of this exhibit. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 916 for print of this negative.
  - Mrs. Hardwick at Draper Company Exhibit at Mechanics' Hall, 1910 (Box 183, Folder 918)
    Negative no.B918. Image depicts a woman identified as Mrs. Hardwick standing in a room with tables, possibly for meals at the exhibit at Mechanics' Hall. She is wearing a light-colored dress with dark stripes in a V-shape on the bodice, and one dark stripe down the skirt to again split into a V-shape on the edges of her overskirt. She is wearing an elaborate dark hat. Mrs. Hardwick was at an exhibit of Draper Company looms at Mechanics Hall in 1910; see Negative 916, in this box, which shows Mrs. Hardwick standing in the middle of a Draper Company display of looms. What connection Mrs. Hardwick has to the Draper Company is unknown. The location of Mechanics Hall is unknown, but it does not seem to resemble the interior of Mechanics Hall in Worcester, Massachusetts The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Massachusetts, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 918 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, June 16, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 934)
    Negative no.B934. June 16, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings (which are off to the right in this image). One man stands in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of it (at least three stories high). A flatbed wagon sits in front. See Negative 935 and Negative 937, in this box, for other images of the pile taken on this date. See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile two months earlier. See Box 181, Negative 896 through Negative 898 for views of this pile taken a month earlier. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 934 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, June 16, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 935)
    Negative no.B935. June 16, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings (which are off to the right in this image). Two men work on boards stretched across sawhorses in the foreground; another man stands off to the right. The man standing at the right gives the viewer a sense of the size of the pile (at least three stories high). See Negative 934 and Negative 937, in this box, for other images of the pile taken on this date. See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile two months earlier. See Box 181, Negative 896 through Negative 898 for views of this pile taken a month earlier. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 935 for print of this negative.
  - Scrap iron pile, Draper Company, June 16, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 937)
    Negative no.B937. June 16, 1911. Image depicts a view of the scrap iron pile outside one of the Draper Company buildings (which are off to the right in this image). One man (who can also be seen in Negative 934, in this box) stands in front of the pile, which gives the viewer a sense of the size of the pile (at least three stories high). A group of male laborers stands on the left. A set of railroad tracks appears to run across the area, with another pile of scrap iron in the left foreground. See Negative 934 and Negative 935 for other images of the pile taken on this date. See also Box 180, Negative 883, which shows the pile two months earlier. See Box 181, Negative 896 through Negative 898 for views of this pile taken a month earlier. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, which explains the extent of the scrap iron pile. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 937 for print of this negative.
  - Draper Company Exhibit, Fall River, Massachusetts, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 942)
    Negative no.B942. June 20, 1911. Image depicts an exhibition of some sort in Fall River, Massachusetts This image shows two Draper looms, the one on the left with a shuttle lying on it and the one on the right showing a loom battery attached to the loom at the right. Behind the looms are tables with a display of bobbins on them, and a mannequin with a woman's dress on it to the right. The display is surrounded by wooden posts topped with a wooden framework that has plants decorating it and lights on it. The photograph is taken from a higher vantage point, possibly a balcony. See Negative 944, in this box, for a broader view of this exhibit room. The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Mass, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 942 for print of this negative.
  - View of Draper Company exhibit, Fall River, Massachusetts, 1911 (Box 185, Folder 944)
    Negative no.B944-A. June 20, 1911. Image depicts an exhibition of some sort in Fall River, Massachusetts This image shows an overall view of the room, with two Draper looms in the lower foreground. The displays in the room are surrounded by wooden posts topped with a wooden framework that has plants decorating it and lights on it. In the right background is a sign "Rogers & Allen School." The photograph is taken from a higher vantage point, possibly a balcony. See Negative 942, in this box, for a closer look at the Draper looms. The Draper Company, located in Hopedale, Massachusetts, manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 3, Item 944 for print of this negative.
  - Train load of Draper Company looms, 1911 (Box 190, Folder 987)
    Negative no.B987. September 30, 1911. Image depicts a railroad train at a depot (which is behind the train and not visible in this image--see Negative 988, in this box), presumably in Hopedale, Massachusetts The train engine pulls a coal car and a long series of closed boxcars that carried Draper Company looms. Two residential buildings can be seen on the left; several sets of railroad tracks intersect in this image. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See also Negative 988, in this box. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 987 for print of this negative. See also, Collection 6612 P, Box 17, Folder 4, Item 987 for print of this negative.
  - Train load of Draper Company looms, 1911 (Box 190, Folder 988)
    Negative no.B988. Train load of Draper Company looms, Hopedale, Massachusetts Gelatin silver print, [1974], from a glass plate negative, September 30, 1911. Image depicts a railroad train at a depot, presumably in Hopedale, Massachusetts The train engine pulls a coal car, and a long series of closed boxcars that carried Draper Company looms. Three men in work clothes pose on top of the first boxcar; two more men are barely visible in the background, posing on the last boxcar. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. See also Negative 987, in this box. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 988 for print of this negative.
  - Closeup view of new Draper Company office building, 1911 (Box 190, Folder 989)
    Negative no.B989. October 6, 1911. Image depicts a close-up view of the company's new office building. The building is a three-story brick structure on the corner of two unknown streets. One side of the building stretches quite a distance down the street into the background. Trees are planted on the street corners. Trolley tracks run down one street. See Negative 990, in this box, for a broader view of the building. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 989 for print of this negative.
  - New Draper Company office building, 1911 (Box 190, Folder 990)
    Negative no.B990. October 6, 1911. Image depicts a broader view of the company's new office building than the one seen in Negative 989, in this box. The building is a three-story brick structure on the corner of two unknown streets. Across the street in the left foreground is a patch of grass, behind which is glimpsed a corner of another building, this one four stories. The streets are wide but unpaved. Trees are planted along the streets. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 990 for print of this negative.
  - Island in Hopedale Pond, 1911 (Box 190, Folder 991)
    Negative no.B991. October 10, 1911. Image depicts a view of an island in the middle of Hopedale Pond in Hopedale, Massachusetts Hopedale Pond was the site of many recreational events, some staged by the Draper Company for its employees. Original photograph by the Draper Company. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 991 for print of this negative.
  - New office floor, Draper Company, 1911 (Box 191, Folder 999)
    Negative no.B999. October 20, 1911. Image depicts a view of a large expanse of open flooring with windows along the left side and at the rear. On the right is a balustrade that overlooks another floor. There is a curving iron stairway about halfway down on the right. Two workmen stand to the left of the stairway. This is probably in the new office building, the exterior of which can also be seen in Negative 989 and Negative 990, in this box. The Draper Company manufactured textile machinery, primarily looms. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 15, Folder 4, Item 999 for print of this negative.
  - Draper Company complex looking northeast (Box 195, Folder 1034)
    Negative no.B1034. ca. 1895. Image depicts a view of the Draper Company complex looking northeast, showing a series of multi-story brick buildings, with a tower in the center. Several smokestacks can be seen, with an especially tall one in the left center. Some houses can be seen off to the right. The machine shop is on the left and the Temple Shop, built for and overseen by W. W. Dutcher, is on the right. In the distant background is a low hill with mostly open ground. In the foreground is open ground, with a few boys standing near the edge of a marsh. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 16, Folder 1, Item 1034 for print of this negative.
  - W. W. Dutcher, Draper Company, 1912 (Box 198, Folder 1074)
    Negative no.B1074. Image depicts Warren W. Dutcher (born 1812), who joined the Draper Company in 1856 and who operated the Temple Shop. Dutcher is shown from the waist up, wearing a dark, three-piece suit, dark bow tie, and white shirt. He is balding and has a white beard. Most likely a photograph of an oil painting. Notation on the reverse of the print reads: "W. W. Dutcher Apr 1, 1912" which is most likely the date this painting was photographed, as Dutcher appears to be in his 60s or 70s, which would place the image about 1880. 8 x 10 in. See Collection 6612 P, Box 16, Folder 1, Item 1074 for print of this negative.